ABHAY R MUNI

BACKEND DEVELOPER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Bangalore, KA India

PHONE

+91 8971391534

EMAIL

abhay@abhayrm.com

LINKS

LinkedIn

GitHub

Devfolio

SKILLS

Node JS

Typescript

Python

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Redis

System Design

Algorithms

AWS

Docker

Kubernetes

LANGUAGES

English, Kannada, Hindi

PROFILE

An enthusiastic backend developer with a strong affinity for Node.js and TypeScript. With a passion for technology that dates back to my school days, spent the past 3 years actively involved in building tech solutions for various startups.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Backend Developer, Akudo

Bangalore

May 2021 — Present

- Successfully managed a distributed system with over 20 services and several cron jobs. Personally developed 7+ full services and implemented 3+ jobs running on Kubernetes.
- Integrated various payment gateways and collaborated with financial partners to support the system currently serving a user base of 2M+ users with over a million monthly transactions.
- Optimised the payments flow leading to reduced failure rates and better fraud detection.
- Contributed to the development of a robust KYC system, streamlining PAN validation and other crucial verification processes.
- Effectively integrated multiple analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Appsflyer, and MoEngage, enabling comprehensive data analysis and insights.
- Constructed a highly efficient contacts service capable of managing millions of contacts promptly, providing users with categorised data within milliseconds. This ensured lower wait time and quick searching.
- Successfully implemented a prepaid recharge feature, leading to a substantial monthly revenue increase of over ₹10L.

Co-founder, NullCrew Technologies

Bangalore

Dec 2019 — Aug 2021

Assisted numerous small and medium businesses in their ventures and addressed their technological requirements. Additionally, ventured into the food-tech industry by establishing two sub-brands, exploring new opportunities and expanding our reach.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (CSE), Sri Venakteshwara College of Engineering

Bangalore

Aug 2017 — Jul 2021

Sri Chaitanya Techno School

Bangalore

Jun 2015 — Mar 2017

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya

Bangalore

Jun 2010 — Mar 2015

Backend Developer Intern, Apnahood

Bangalore

Apr 2021 — Jun 2021

During the 3-month internship at Apnahood, a product-based company specialising in the hyperlocal space, I played a pivotal role as a Backend Development Intern. In addition to engineering, I actively contributed to core operations and planning, providing a comprehensive understanding of the company's functions.

Web Developer Intern, Hawx Media

Bangalore

Jan 2020 — Mar 2020

As an intern at Hawx Media, a service-based company specialising in web consultancy, I gained my first ever valuable real-world experience in web design and development during my 3-month tenure.

TOP PROJECTS

WSN Smart Grids for Continuous Power Supply and Monitoring

Dec 2018 — Dec 2020

Microprocessor Programmer, Backend Programmer, Network Analyst

A product designed to ensure continuous power supply and monitor the same in real-time and intimate faults automatically. Funded by Vision Group of Science and Technology, Govt. of Karnataka, under the scheme K-FIST(L1).

GoKhareedo

Apr 2020 — May 2020

Backend Programmer, DevOps Engineer

A web app designed and launched as a solution for CoVid struggles and also made live. It allowed customers to order from nearby stores and the shopkeepers could keep the requested items ready.

Call-amity

Feb 2020 — Mar 2020

Backend Programmer, DevOps Engineer

A portal designed to manage ourselves at a calamity with much needed yet unique features. Nominated among the top 9 projects at OnLoad 2.0, a national level hackathon.

PUBLICATIONS

Wireless Network Smart Grid for Continuous Power Supply and Monitoring

Published "Wireless Network Smart Grid for Continuous Power Supply and Monitoring" in the SCOPUS indexed journal - International Journal of Recent Technology and Engineering, ISSN: 2277-3878, Volume-8 Issue-3, September 2019.